export const quizQuestions = {
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary source of energy for most power grids around the world?",
        choices: [
          "Solar power",
          "Wind power",
          "Fossil fuels",
          "Hydropower",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Fossil fuels",
      },
      {
        question: "How does electricity typically travel from power plants to consumers?",
        choices: [
          "Through water pipes",
          "Via transmission and distribution networks",
          "Directly from generators to homes",
          "Through the internet",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Via transmission and distribution networks",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why is energy efficiency important in homes and businesses?",
        choices: ["It increases energy consumption",
         "It leads to higher energy costs",
         "It reduces energy bills and environmental impact",
         "It has no impact on the environment"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "It reduces energy bills and environmental impact",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the primary goal of demand management in energy usage?",
        choices: [
          "To increase the overall energy consumption", 
          "To balance energy supply and demand", 
          "To eliminate the use of renewable energy sources", 
          "To double the energy costs for consumers"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To balance energy supply and demand",
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a common method used in demand management to encourage lower energy use during peak hours?",
        choices: [
          "Increasing energy prices during off-peak hours",
          "Providing incentives for high energy consumption",
          "Offering lower rates or incentives for using less energy during peak times",
          "Discouraging the use of energy-efficient appliances",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Offering lower rates or incentives for using less energy during peak times",
      },
      {
        question: "Benefits to the consumer from demand management include?",
        choices: [
          "Higher energy bills",
          "Less control over their energy use",
          "Savings on their electricity bill",
          "Reduced internet connectivity",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Savings on their electricity bill",
      },
      {
        question: "How does implementing demand management strategies benefit the environment?",
        choices: [
          "By significantly increasing carbon emissions",
          "By reducing reliance on fossil fuels and lowering carbon emissions",
          "By eliminating the need for public transportation",
          "By discouraging the use of renewable energy",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "By reducing reliance on fossil fuels and lowering carbon emissions",
      },
      {
        question: "What can be a direct benefit of participating in a demand management program for consumers?",
        choices: [
          "Higher energy bills",
          "Less control over their energy use",
          "Savings on their electricity bill",
          "Reduced internet connectivity",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Savings on their electricity bill",
      },
      {
        question: "Why is load shifting important in demand management?",
        choices: [
          "It increases the energy load during peak times",
          "It shifts energy usage to times when demand is higher",
          "It helps balance the power grid by using energy during lower-demand periods",
          "It makes energy more expensive during off-peak hours",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "It helps balance the power grid by using energy during lower-demand periods",
      },

      {
        question: "Which of the following electric loads can be effectively managed as part of a demand management program?",
        choices: [
          "Fixed lighting systems in public areas",
          "Emergency medical equipment",
          "Residential air conditioning units",
          "Data centers that require constant cooling",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Residential air conditioning units",
      },
      
    ],
  };